Annagrace Blount

704-999-3971 | blountannagrace@gmail.com | 12001 Olympic Club Drive, Charlotte, North Carolina

Summary

Hard-working and passionate student at the University of North Carolina Charlotte. Majoring in Communication Studies with a concentration in Public Advocacy to achieve my goals of improving animal welfare. Career highlights include managing a rapidly growing business with over 200 customers and starting my own small business in which I manage over 100 clients throughout the year. Skilled in customer service, pet care, digital and computer systems, as well as communication. Experience working in fast-paced environments and client-oriented settings.

Experience

Care With A Cause | Charlotte, North Carolina Pet Services Provider | 02/2022 - Present

After parting with Rover, I decided to continue working in pet services and found new clients to care for and work with. I currently still work in this profession and my responsibilities are the same as they were with Rover; feeding, walking, and administering care for pets in the absence of their owners. In this capacity, however, I have learned much more about operating a small business as efficiently as possible. From balancing books, managing my calendar and schedule, and continually striving to improve client satisfaction, I have taken on much more responsibility which has resulted in an increased ability to stay organized, manage my time more effectively, and growth in communication skills.

Rover | Charlotte, North Carolina Pet Sitter | 06/2021 - 02/2022

During my time with Rover, I gained experience with multiple types of dogs and cats. My responsibilities included dog walking, visits to feed and check on pets, as well as general pet care and home maintenance. I also improved responsibilities included dog walking, visits to feed and check on pets, as well as general pet care and home maintenance. I also improved on customer relations and client satisfaction, making sure that every need stipulated by my clients was surpassed. This opportunity allowed me to improve in communication, time management, and organizational skills. I also improved my skills pertaining to pets and the ability to adapt to new situations quickly and frequently.

DogWorld Dog Park | Kannapolis, North Carolina DogWorld Manager and Representative | 12/2020 - 05/2021

In this position, I oversaw dogs playing within a 16 acre park, as well as communicating and interacting with their owners to learn about their pet and understand their backgrounds. My responsibilities included detailed observation, interaction with pets and their owners, customer service, and dog screening. I also handled the creation and issuance of flyers, acted as security for the park and making sure only members were entering the premises, as well as handling payment and any other questions or concerns that occurred. When I began working here, the park had little customer interaction in-person and online. After workign closely with the owner, I helped to transform the park into a profitable and popular business with over 500 customers. Throught the introduction and implementation of neThrought the introduction and implementation of new ideas, policies, and practices, the business grew exponentially within a matter of months and went viral on several social media platforms. Through this oppurtunity, I gained a glimpse into how a startup business can grow and what it takes to do so, I also gained more experience with people and pets of all temperments. I was unofficially designated the "conflict specialist" and would handle any issues that arose throughout the park, with pets and people alike. Another skillset I gained through this oppurtunity was attention to detail. While monitoring several acres with upwards of 30 dogs present at any given time... awareness, attention, quick thinkinh, and problem solving were crucial skills to possess, which I expanded upon during my time there.

K9 Playland | Charlotte, North Carolina Kennel Attendant | 06/2019 - 10/2019

In this position, I interacted with pets of all sizes and temperaments, while overseeing interactions and maintaining a clean indoor and outdoor environment. I also assisted in cleaning kennels, administering meals and medications, and creating reports on clients pets. My responsibilities included watching groups of dogs, cleaning up after them, and assisting them in and out of their kennels, as well as monitoring play efficiently to ensure safety of all present pets. My most important role was offering support and care to pets who were away from the comfort of their home and owners. Through this opportunity, I learned about different types of dogs, how to care for them, and how to read their body language. I grew tremendously through this experience and understanding how to care for multiple pets at one time.

Front Desk Receptionist | 06/2018 - 09/2018

In this position, I interacted with customers and their pets, helping them to create appointments and handling payment services. My responsibilities included answering the phone, scheduling appointments, assisting customers with requests, and helping to clean up around the grooming station. Through this oppurtunity, I gained insight into the innerworkings of a small business, how to use their digital systems, as well as improving upong my customer service and social skills.

Skills

Organizational skills, Communication Skills, Customer Service, Critical Thinking and Problem Solving, Digital Skills, Design, Project Management, Writing Skills, Proficient in Foreign Languages, Computer Proficiency, Leadership, Time management, Animal Care, Dog Handling, Kennel Experience, Shelter Experience, Community Oriented

Education

University of North Carolina Charlotte | Charlotte, North Carolina Communication Studies - Public Advocacy | 05/2023

- · Currently completing courses in Persuasion, Public Advocacy, Global and Mass Media.
- · Volunteered on a monthly basis with shelters in South Carolina.
- Majoring in Communication Studies with a concentration in Public Advocacy and a minor in American Studies.